Guide to the Nichols Family Correspondence
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Correspondence, 1769-1873; Series I; 6.67; (19 boxes)
  - Nichols, John Bowyer, 1779-1863
    - ALS to Octavian Blewitt, Parliament St., 1840 Feb 4 (Box 13)
      Concerns the work of the Royal Literary Fund.
    - ALS (draft) to [William Bray], Parliament St., [1828 or later] (Box 13)
    - ALS to Edward William Brayley, [n.p.], 1826 Feb 22 (Box 13)
    - ALS to Sir Egerton Brydges, Parliament St., 1832 Aug 4 (Box 13)
      Thanks Brydges for referral to newly published book.
    - AL (3d person, draft) to Charles Burney, [n.p.], [1812] (Box 13)
      Concerns the printing of a revised edition of Burney's Philemon.
    - Letter (draft) to W. Edwards, [n.p.], 1821 Jan 5 (Box 13)
      Hopes that Edwards "may enjoy for many years to come an honorable Retirement from the bustle of Business."
    - ALS (draft) to Sir Henry Ellis, [n.p.], n.d. (Box 13)
      Relays request.
    - Letter (copy) to James Ford, [n.p.], 1839 May 9 (Box 13)
      Answers Ford's questions about recent publications in the field of county histories.
    - ALS to T. D. Fosbroke, Hammersmith, 1840 Oct 5 (Box 13)
    - 2 ALS (drafts) to Mr. Harrison, [n.p.], 1837 Sep 30 (Box 13)
      About the estate and sister of Thomas Fisher.
    - Letter (copy) to John Herrick, [n.p.], 1826 Nov 16 (Box 13)
      On articles for the Gentleman's Magazine.
    - Letter (copy) to Mrs. George Hollis, [n.p.], 1843 Oct 21 (Box 13)
      Consoles Mrs. Hollis on the death of her son Thomas who worked as an engraver for Nichols.
    - ALS to T. Hooker, Parliament St., 1824 Aug 4 (Box 13)
      Concerns the publication and sale of a manuscript.
    - 1 ALS and 3 ALS (drafts) to Catherine Hutton, [n.p.], 1815-1817 Dec 1 (Box 13)
      On the publication of her Journey to London and the re-issue of her father's History of Derby.
    - ALS to T. Little, [n.p.], 1847 Jul 16 (Box 13)
    - ALS (draft) to Sir Samuel Mayricke, [n.p.], 1836 Feb 6 (Box 13)
      Thanks Mayricke for writing an article for the Gentleman's Magazine.
    - 2 ALS (drafts) to John Nichols, [n.p.], 1826 Mar 18, Nov 24 (Box 13)
      Concerns personal affairs. Second letter was the last John Bowyer wrote to his father.
    - ALS to Mary Nichols, [n.p.], 1852 Mar 30 (Box 13)
      To his daughter expressing his happiness that she has started to collect letters. He gives a few hints on ways to improve her collection and advises her to avoid forged autographs of Byron and Shelley.
    - ALS (draft) to Mr. Parker, [n.p.], 1841 Feb 20 (Box 13)
      Sends a copy of Warburton's Literary Remains.
    - ALS to Thomas Joseph Pettigrew, [n.p.], 1819 Dec 23 (Box 13)
      About payment for printing sermon.
    - 3 ALS to John Taylor, Parliament St., 1826 Sep 4-1827 Feb 1 (Box 13)
      On personal affairs, such as Nichols's description of his father's death, and book publishing business.
    - ALS to an unnamed recipient, [n.p.], 1825 Sep 30 (Box 13)
      Sends thanks for recently received publications.
    - AL (draft) to unnamed recipient, [n.p.], [1826 or later] (Box 13)
      Concerns corrections of proofs.
    - ALS to unnamed recipient, Parliament St., 1827 May 19 (Box 13)
      Nichols is "sorry to hear of your difficulties and illness, but really think you should not have embarked on such a speculation as printing a new Edition of 'Gazman' at my Risk."
    - ALS to unnamed recipient, [n.p.], 1827 Dec 27 (Box 13)
      Declines request for assistance on research for a biography of Samuel Parr, since Nichols & Co. is publishing a work on his life at this time.
    - ALS to unnamed recipient, [n.p.], 1832 Aug 22 (Box 13)
      Declines to buy books offered the recipient.
    - ALS (draft) to unnamed recipient, [n.p.], [1836 or later] (Box 13)
      About the death of Thomas Fisher.
    - ALS (draft) to unnamed recipient, [n.p.], [1838 or later] (Box 13)
    - ALS (draft) to unnamed recipient, Parliament St., 1846 Dec 23 (Box 13)
      Description of an article in the Gentleman's Magazine.
    - ALS to unnamed recipient, [n.p.], n.d. (Box 13)
      Instructions to an employee.
    - Advertisement (draft) for a new edition of Thomas Fisher's History of Bedfordshire, Hoxton, 1836 Aug 1 (Box 13)
    - "Epithalium", [n.p.], 1830 Apr 1 (Box 13)
      Holograph.
  - Nichols, John Gough, 1806-1873
    - ALS to Edward George Ballard, Parliament St., [1842] Nov 8 (Box 13)
      Offers Ballard a job doing "transcription."
    - ALS to William Lisle Bowles, [n.p.], 1828 Sep (Box 13)
      Describes a "Tot-hill" he found in Staffordshire.
    - ALS to Sir John Bernard Burke, Parliament St., 1870 Jun 11 (Box 13)
    - ALS to Peter Burke, Eaton Place, 1866 Oct 15 (Box 13)
    - ALS to Peter Cunningham, Upper Harley Pl., 1852 Aug 1 (Box 13)
      Provides biographical information about John and John Bowyer Nichols so that Cunningham may enlarge their notices in the Handbook of London.
    - ALS to Joseph French, Cloisters, [n.y.] Sep 3 (Box 13)
      Sends portraits and autographs.
    - ALS to George Godwin, Parliament St., [n.y.] (Box 13)
      Encloses the list of the subscribers to the Camden Society.
    - ALS to T. Hapleton, [n.p.], n.d. (Box 13)
    - ALS to Mr. Irving, [n.p.], n.d. (Box 13)
      On Gentleman's Magazine and personal affairs.
    - ALS to Sir Frederic Madden, Parliament St., 1848 May 9 (Box 13)
      About Edwin Guest's article in the May 1848 issue of Gentleman's Magazine (pp. 487-94). Madden's response in the following month (pp. 600-04).
    - ALS (3d person, draft) to Charles Marriott, [n.p.], [1829] (Box 13)
      Advises Marriott that the Gentleman's Magazine will be unable to print his obituary of George Gaskin due to its length.
    - ALS to John Martin, [n.p.], 1833 Dec 27 (Box 13)
    - ALS to Sir Samuel Meyrick, Parliament St., 1846 May 15 (Box 13)
      Describes a "steel shield or target" on exhibit at the Society of Antiquaries. Reports that it has recently been purchased by the Board of Ordinance for the town collection.
    - ALS to Anne Nichols, Parliament St., 1826 May 24 (Box 13)
      About the Nichols's family's and friends' health and activity.
    - AL (draft) to John Nichols, [n.p.], 1826 Oct (Box 13)
    - 8 ALS to John Bowyer Nichols, Parliament St., 1826 May-1860 Oct 22 (Box 13)
      About personal affairs, such as dinner engagements and family reunions, and the publishing business.
    - 2 ALS to John Woody Papworth, Woburn, 1862 Aug 25, 31 (Box 14)
      Concerns the publication of Papworth's works.
    - ALS to Mr. Parke, Parliament St., 1871 Mar 24 (Box 14)
      Encourages Parke to complete his History of Brewood and discusses genealogical and antiquarian matters.
    - ALS to Edward Peacock, Parliament St., 1870 Dec 21 (Box 14)
      Confirms his readiness to recommend Peacock for membership in the Society of Antiquaries.
    - ALS to James Robinson Planché, Parliament St., 1838 May 16 (Box 14)
      Asks for engravings that will appear in a review of Planché's Royal Records in the next Gentleman's Magazine.
    - ALS to W. Radclyffe, [n.p.], n.d. (Box 14)
      Solicits book order.
    - ALS to John Richards, Parliament St., 1835 Sep 24 (Box 14)
      Arranges meeting. Accompanied by a draft of the same letter.
    - 2 ALS to Charles Roach Smith, Parliament St., 1857 Sep 26 (Box 14)
      About engravings appearing in an article on Roman coins.
    - ALS to Richard Thomson, Parliament St., [n.y.] Apr 27 (Box 14)
    - ALS to Edward Wilton, Brighton, [1863 or later] Mar 21 (Box 14)
      Sends thanks for certain comments and flattering remarks to do with his present magazine.
    - ALS to unnamed recipient, [n.p.], 1836 Oct 29 (Box 14)
      Requests that the recipient read the proofs of a forthcoming history of Northumberland.
    - ALS to unnamed recipient, Parliament St., 1863 Jun 14 (Box 14)
      Asks for information about armor and military dress.
    - ALS to unnamed recipient, Westminster, 1871 Mar 21 (Box 14)
      Inquires about the possibility of publishing some of the recipient's works. Such a project had been discussed previously with John Bowyer Nichols.
    - ALS to unnamed recipient, [n.p.], n.d. (Box 14)
      About an article for the Gentleman's Magazine.
    - "Obituary of John Nichols", 1826 Nov 26 (Box 14)
      Holograph. "Every family has its great men, and he was the great man of ours ..."
    - Prospectus for The Progresses of James I, [n.p.], [1828] (Box 14)
      Holograph. Prospectus for John Nichols's book published in 1828. Accompanied by two reviews of The Progresses of Queen Elizabeth.
  - Nichols, R. AL (3d person) to Nichols & Co., Wakefield, 1823 Sep 24 (Box 14)
  - Nichols, Sarah, 1771-1843. ALS to John Bowyer Nichols, [n.p.], 1831 May (Box 14)
    Asks for his kind assistance and advice on the purchase of a drawing.
  - Nichols & Co., printers, London. AL to W. Boyle Breyes, Parliament St., 1848 Feb 7 (Box 14)
    Agrees to print a general index of the Gentleman's Magazine covering 1819-1847 with Breyes as a one-third partner.
  - Nicol, William
    - ALS to John Bowyer Nichols, [n.p.], 1830 Oct 5 (Box 14)
      About the memoirs of William Bulmer.
    - ALS to John Gough Nichols, Cleveland Road, 1830 Oct 18 (Box 14)
      Asks to see the memoirs of William Bulmer. An extract from the memoirs is attached to the letter.
  - Nicolas, Charles. AL (3d person) to John Bowyer Nichols, Hoston, 1824 Jul 26 (Box 14)
    Asks Nichols to "enclose the accompanying letters in his next parcel to his brother Nicholas Harris Nicolas."
  - Nicolas, Sir John Nicholas Harris, 1799-1848
    - ALS to John Nichols, Portman Square, 1825 Jan 31 (Box 14)
    - 7 ALS to John Bowyer Nichols, [v.p.], 1824 Jan 28-1839 Mar 25 (Box 14)
      About the Gentleman's Magazine, his publications and his health.
    - 7 ALS to John Bowyer Nichols, [v.p.], 1824 Mar 12-1830 Sep 8 (Box 14)
      About various antiquarian and literary subjects including articles for the Gentleman's Magazine and Archaeologia.
    - 6 ALS to John Gough Nichols, Bedford Row, 1828 Apr 24-1839 Feb 20 (Box 14)
      About articles for the Gentleman's Magazine on the Society of Antiquaries and manuscripts. Mentions Sir Frederic Madden.
    - AL (3d person) to Nichols & Co., [n.p.], [1832] (Box 14)
      Instructions for the printing of his pamphlet.
  - Noble, Elizabeth. ALS to [John Gough Nichols?], Richmond Terrace, 1856 Apr 19 (Box 14)
    Invites Nichols to the consecration of a new church.
  - Norfolk, Charlotte Sophia (Leveson- Gower) Howard, Duchess of, 1788-1870. AL (3d person) to John Bowyer Nichols, [n.p.], n.d. (Box 14)
    About the History of Suffolk.
  - Northampton, Spencer Joshua Alwyne Compton, 3d Marquis of, 1790-1851. AL (3d person) to John Gough Nichols, Torquay, 1845 Mar 25 (Box 14)
    Agrees on an engraving.
  - Nuttall, P. A. ALS to John Bowyer Nichols, Kings Terrace North, Pentonville, 1839 Jan 6 (Box 14)
    Inquires about the copyright to John Nichols's Literary Anecdotes.
  - Page, Angela. ALS to John Gough Nichols, Ampton, 1832 Feb 22 (Box 15)
    On the proofs for a publication of hers.
  - Paget, Francis Edward, 1806-1882. ALS to Nichols & Co., [n.p.], n.d. (Box 15)
    Places his name on subscribers list to "Erdleswich."
  - Palgrave, Sir Francis, 1788-1861. AL (3d person) to John Bowyer Nichols, Parliament St., 1824 Feb 16 (Box 15)
    Declines dinner invitation.
  - Palmer, Archdale. ALS to John Bowyer Nichols, Fenchurch St., [1814 or later] Jan 13 (Box 15)
    Concerns the application of Nichols's son for enrollment at St. Paul's School. Accompanied by Nichols's draft reply.
  - Palmer, Elizabeth. ALS to [John Bowyer Nichols], Hyde Park, n.d. (Box 15)
    Encloses "the lines address'd by Miss Holford [later Mrs. Margaret Hodson] to the late Mr. Palmer some Years since while residing at Clifton."
  - Palmer, J. ALS to Nichols & Co., Grays Inn, 1832 Feb 25 (Box 15)
    Obituary of Margaret O'Brien for the Gentleman's Magazine.
  - Palmer, Joseph, 1756-1815
    - 32 ALS to John Nichols, [v.p.], 1792 Apr 20-1813 Sep 20 (Box 15)
      Letters between author and publisher. Palmer was a frequent contributor to Gentleman's Magazine.
    - 13 ALS to John Bowyer Nichols, [v.p.], 1807 Nov 20-1814 Dec 3 (Box 15)
      Business and personal letters between writer and publisher. Accompanied by Nichols's draft replies to some of Palmer's letters.
    - 14 ALS to Nichols & Co., Clifton, Bristol, 1809 Nov 12-1813 Feb 23 (Box 15)
      Letters between writer and his publishers.
    - Dedication, signed, to William Noble, Clifton Bristol, 1810 Apr 17 (Box 15)
      Expresses his love and gratitude to the man he esteemed more than any other on earth. This letter served as the dedication to the third edition of Palmer's Rambler.
  - Park, Mr. AL to [Nichols & Co.], [n.p.], 1843 Apr (Box 15)
    Returns History of Fulham.
  - Parker, John Henry, 1806-1884. ALS to John Gough Nichols, Oxford, 1836 Sep 19 (Box 15)
    Thanks Nichols for the notice of Parker's Glossary of Architecture in the Gentleman's Magazine.
  - Parkes, David, 1763-1833. 2 ALS to [Nichols & Co.], Shrewsbury, 1817 Dec 18-1819 Aug 14 (Box 15)
    About drawings of churches and castles for Gentleman's Magazine.
  - Parry, John Docwra, fl. 1827. 9 ALS to John Bowyer Nichols, [v.p.], 1832 Mar 12-1859 Jul 11 (Box 15)
    Destitute writer asks for sympathy and relief from Royal Literary Fund. Accompanied by letter to the editor of the Gentleman's Magazine.
  - Parry, John Docwra, d. 1833? ALS to Mr. Nichols, [n.p.], [n.y.] Dec 28 (Box 15)
  - Paver, William, 1802-1871. ALS to John Bowyer Nichols, York, 1835 May 13 (Box 15)
    Sends pedigree of the Markenfield Family to the Gentleman's Magazine.
  - Payne & Foss, firm. AL to [John Bowyer Nichols?], Pallellale, 1830 Mar 19 (Box 15)
    About the delivery of a book ordered by Mark Davis.
  - Pearson, Richard
    - ALS to John Bowyer Nichols, Crescent, Bedford, 1838 Jan 15 (Box 15)
    - ALS to Nichols & Co., Bedford, 1838 Jan 8 (Box 15)
      About the publication of a pamphlet on medical instructions and the ms.
  - Pemberton, Richard Laurence, 1831-1901. ALS to John Gough Nichols, The Barnes, Sunderland, 1866 Jun 25 (Box 15)
    Protests his family's omission from the latest edition of Shirley's Noble and Gentle Men of England. He describes in detail his family's genealogy.
  - Pettigrew, Thomas Joseph, 1791-1865. ALS to [Nichols & Co.], London, [n.y.] Aug 26 (Box 15)
    Asks whether the Gentleman's Magazine would publish the literary works of his friend, Mr. Wilkinson.
  - Pidgeon, Henry Clark, 1807-1880. 7 ALS to John Gough Nichols, Shrewsbury, 1831 Sep 25-1835 Jul 20 (Box 15)
    About his letters, articles, reviews, and poetry for the Gentleman's Magazine.
  - Planta, Joseph, 1744-1827. ALS to John Nichols, British Museum, 1787 Apr 20 (Box 15)
    Expresses the gratitude of the British Museum for Nichol's gift "of a parcel of Autograph Letters of Sir Richard Steel."
  - Pleydell, colonel. AL (3d person) to John Bowyer Nichols, Portman St., 1815 Feb 15 (Box 15)
    Thanks Nichols for the portrait of a friend.
  - Pleydell, Mr. AL (3d person) to John Nichols, Portman Sq., 1808 Jul 30 (Box 15)
  - Plumptree, James, 1771-1832. Letter (copy) to John Bowyer Nichols, Great Gransden Vicarage, 1831 Mar 22 (Box 16)
    Sends Nichols an article about drama for his inspection.
  - Potts, Cuthbert. 2 ALS to [John Nichols], Kingsdown, 1807 Aug 20-1819 Apr 27 (Box 16)
    Concerns antiquarian matters and corrections for an article.
  - Powis, Edward Clive, 6th Earl, 1754-1839. ALS to [Nichols & Co.], [n.p.], [n.y.] Jun 29 (Box 16)
  - Poynder, John, 1779-1849. 2 ALS to John Bowyer Nichols, Bridewell, 1839 Dec 11, 1840 Dec 7 (Box 16)
    About articles and back issues of the Gentleman's Magazine.
  - Pratt, Samuel Jackson, 1749-1814. 2 ALS to John Nichols, [n.p.], 1806 Jan 16, Feb 4 (Box 16)
    Sends review for publications in the Gentleman's Magazine.
  - Prior, Sir James, 1790?-1869. ALS to John Bowyer Nichols, Athenaeum, 1831 May 9 (Box 16)
    Asks for materials Nichols might have concerning Oliver Goldsmith for a biography Prior plans to write.
  - Prosser, George Frederick. ALS to John Bowyer Nichols, Ockham, 1835 Dec 30 (Box 16)
    Explains why he has been delayed in finishing another portion of his book.
  - Prout, John Skinner, 1806-1876. AL to Mr. Nichols, 1859 Jun 15 (Box 16)
    Mr. Prout "called to ask if Mr. Nichols would oblige him with Mrs. Greeley's address."
  - Rackett, Thomas, 1757-1841 (Box 16)
    - ALS to John Bowyer Nichols, Spetisbury, 1835 May 25 (Box 16)
      "My dear Sir, It is very desirable that a tribute of respect should be paid our late invaluable friend Dr. Maton, and in compliance with your wishes on the subject I shall."
    - 2 ALS to John Gough Nichols, Spetisbury, 1835 Sep 18-1836 Jul 9 (Box 16)
      First letter concerns a memoir he has written on W. G. Maton, the physician; the second thanks Nichols for accounts of two places of antiquarian interest.
  - Radnor, Jacob Pleydell-Bouverie, 6th Earl of, 1750-1828. ALS to John Nichols, Folkestone, 1795 Oct 6 (Box 16)
    Buys subscription to Nichols's History of Leicestershire.
  - Radnor, William Pleydell-Bouverie, 7th Earl of, 1779-1869 (Box 16)
    - ALS to Mr. Nichols, 1804 Jul 12 (Box 16)
    - ALS to Nichols & Co., Salisbury, 1845 Mar 25 (Box 16)
      Seeks to return unsolicited volumes sent by Nichols.
  - Redgrave, Richard, 1804-1888. ALS to Mrs. Lucy Nichols, Hyde Park, 1851 Feb 14 (Box 16)
    Sends his autograph.
  - Rees, Owen, 1770-1837. ALS to John Bowyer Nichols, Paternoster Row, 1814 Oct 13 (Box 16)
    Wants information about a John Brown who was a minister in London about 1774. Includes Nichols's draft reply.
  - Repton, John Adey, 1775-1860. ALS to John Bowyer Nichols, [n.p.], n.d. (Box 16)
    Hopes that Nichols's health improves, discusses the letters of Deane Swift and quotes one of Bolingbroke to Swift.
  - Reynolds, Thomas, 1752-1829. ALS to Nichols & Co., Little Bowden, 1818 Apr 7 (Box 16)
    Mr. Reynolds "shall be obliged to you to send a copy of the Her Britanniarum in Boards to the Chief Engraver."
  - Richardson, Mr. ALS to [Nichols & Co.], [n.p.], 1812 Apr 5 (Box 16)
    Concerns the proofs of his article.
  - Richardson, William, 1794-1837. ALS to John Bowyer Nichols, Cambridge, 1822 Apr 5, 1823 Apr 23 (Box 16)
    The first letter offers to purchase two works of LeNeve if Nichols will wait until the end of the year. The second apologizes for paying so tardily.
  - Rivers, William Horace Pitt-Rivers, 3d Baron, 1777-1828. AL (3d person) to [John Bowyer Nichols], Stratfield, [1828] Jan 21 (Box 16)
  - Rivington, Francis, 1805-1885. ALS to John Bowyer Nichols, Waterloo Place, 1837 Dec 2 (Box 16)
  - Rivington, John, 1779-1841. ALS to John Bowyer Nichols, [n.p.], 1830 Apr 2 (Box 16)
    Concerns bills for books.
  - Robertson, David, 1795-1854. ALS and AL (3d person) to John Bowyer Nichols, Great George St., 1831 Oct 27 (Box 16)
    About Andrew Strahan's legacy to Nichols.
  - Roby, Henry Wood. ALS to Messrs. Nichols & Son, Tamworth, 1826 Jul 20 (Box 16)
  - Roby, John, d. 1839
    - ALS to John Bowyer Nichols, Swansea, 1821 Nov 21 (Box 16)
      Includes memorial for Henry Wood, Esq., to be printed in Gentleman's Magazine. Reminds Nichols of his desire to know who a certain J. Roby is.
    - ALS to [Nichols & Co.], Swansea, 1821 May 22 (Box 16)
      Adds a birth note to the Gentleman's Magazine. Requests again to be sent information on a certain J. Roby, author of several poems.
  - Roby, John, 1793-1850
    - 2 ALS to John Nichols, Swansea, 1816 Aug 10, 1820 Jun 7 (Box 16)
      About research for a history of Bedfordshire and Dorset.
    - ALS to John Nichols, Swansea, 1816 Aug 15 (Box 16)
      Letter to printer asking when his work will appear. Together with demographic and topographical notes concerning Bedfordshire.
  - Roffe, Edwin. ALS to John Gough Nichols, [n.p.], 1864 Feb 12 (Box 16)
    About proof corrections.
  - Rosser, William Henry. 10 ALS and AL (3d person) to John Bowyer Nichols, Grays Inn Place, 1830 Feb 16-1831 Dec 2 (Box 16)
    About the Society of Noviomagus, of which Rosser was secretary.
  - Rowtree, John. ALS to Mr. Glendinning, Darlington, 1803 Nov 15 (Box 16)
    Asks Glendinning to contact John Nichols and procure a set of the plates from William Hutchinson's History of the County of Durham, which Rowtree planned to reprint.
  - Sandys of Ombersley, Edwin Sandys, 2d Baron, 1726-1797. AL (3d person) to John Nichols, Bruton St. (Box 17)
    Orders a book.
  - Schnebbelie, Jacob, 1760-1792. ALS to John Nichols, Poland St. (Box 17)
    Letter to the Editor of the Gentleman's Magazine about old coins.
  - Scott, P. N. ALS to John Bowyer Nichols, Norwich, 1847 Jan 11 (Box 17)
    Sends an account of the life of Joseph John Gurney.
  - Scott, Sir Walter, Bart., 1771-1832. Letter (copy) to John Gough Nichols, [n.p.], 1829 Dec 8 (Box 17)
  - Scrope, George Julius Poulett, 1792-1876. ALS to John Gough Nichols, Belgrave Square, 1852 Mar 25 (Box 17)
    Scrope is "much obliged by your offer of a copy of your Catalogue of the Stourhead Library."
  - Serres, Olivia (Wilmot), 1772-1834. 2 ALS to John Nichols, [n.p.], 1822 Aug 26 (Box 17)
  - Setchel, Sarah, 1803-1894. ALS to Miss Buchanan, London (Box 17)
    Expresses regret that she is unable, due to failing eyesight, to do the portraiture of (Nichols or Buchanan?). Refers her to another artist.
  - Shepherd, Isherwood and Shepherd, firm. ALS to John Bowyer Nichols, Doctors Commons, 1826 Dec 30 (Box 17)
    Concerns the wills of the most recently deceased Joseph Cradock and John Nichols.
  - Sherborne, W. Penny. ALS to unnamed recipient, [n.p.], 1803 Aug 23 (Box 17)
    Asks recipient to alert Nichols & Co. to an error in Hutchinson's History of Dorset.
  - Sherlock, Martin, d. 1797. ALS to John Nichols, Ballina, Castlebar, 1783 Mar 17 (Box 17)
  - Short, Thomas
    - ALS to John Bowyer Nichols, Hinckley, 1863 Jan 14 (Box 17)
      Finds Thomas Hiffe deserving of a contribution from the Hinckley Relief Fund.
    - ALS to John Gough Nichols, Hinckley, 1863 Jan 16 (Box 17)
      Acknowledges Nichols's gift for the Hinckley Relief Fund.
  - Singer, Samuel Weller, 1783-1858. ALS to [John Nichols?], Buskey, 1819 Nov 22 (Box 17)
  - Skipton, George. ALS (fragment) to John Gough Nichols, [n.p.], [1862 or later] (Box 17)
    Wants Nichols or another qualified genealogist to write a history of his family.
  - Sloman, C. ALS to John Bowyer Nichols, Yarmouth, 1829 Nov 26 (Box 17)
    About the subscription list for Faby's East Anglican Glossary.
  - Smirke, Sydney, 1798-1877. ALS to unnamed recipient, [n.p.], [1847] Jan 21 (Box 17)
    Admits Mr. Nichols to see the interior of the new Parliamentary buildings.
  - Smith, John. ALS to John Bowyer Nichols, Vicarage Ealing, 1847 Mar 2 (Box 17)
    Congratulatory note.
  - Somerset, Lord Granville Charles Henry, 1792-1848. 2 AL (3d person) to John Bowyer Nichols, [n.p.], 1828 Mar 13, 17 (Box 17)
    Arranges meetings to discuss publishing.
  - Southgate, J. H. ALS to John Bowyer Nichols, Fleet Street, 1837 Mar 31-Apr 1 (Box 17)
    About business matters; with draft reply from Nichols.
  - Southill, Robert. ALS to John Bowyer Nichols, Cork, 1830 Aug 11 (Box 17)
    Letter to the editor of the Gentleman's Magazine which includes a copy of a letter by Oliver Cromwell.
  - Sparke, Bowyer Edward, Bp. of Ely, d. 1836. AL (3d person) to John Bowyer Nichols, Ely House, 1821 Feb 23 (Box 17)
    Arranges for meeting.
  - Staines, Joseph. ALS to John Gough Nichols, Newport Pagnell, 1842 Jun 7 (Box 17)
    Letter to the editor of the Gentleman's Magazine supplying added details to a previous article.
  - Stamford, George Harry Grey, 6th earl of, 1765-1845. AL to Nichols & Son, Dunham Massey, Altrincham, 1822 Jul 6 (Box 17)